

Phone: 863-797-7465 scottmathis7185@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/scott-mathis github.com/ScottMathis4

About Me:

I served as an officer in the Air Force 10 years and afterward owned and operated a small business agency 14 years. My education and experience is in financial management. Throughout my career I have tackled the challenges of analyzing operations to improve efficiency and effectiveness. I like to piece together puzzles and figure out how things work. These qualities fit perfectly for pursuing a career in data analytics. Outside of work, I enjoy camping, sports and playing table tennis.

Skills:

- SQL
- SSIS/SSRS in SQL Server
- Python
- Power BI, Tableau (data visualization tools)
- Excel (Pivot tables, VLOOKUP, etc)
- Git/GitHub

Technical Education:

Data Analytics Apprentice

Nashville Software School | September 2021- Current

Four-month intensive program in data analytics and business intelligence. Emphasis on analytical reasoning through hands-on training in every stage of the analytics workflow.

Projects include:

App Trader -|- Team Project

Four team members collaborated to determine the most profitable mobile applications for a fictional app brokerage firm. Analyzed data using PostgreSQL and recommended a top 10 list of mobile apps which should be purchased based on projected profitability. Communicated findings through PowerPoint presentation.

GDP and Internet Usage - |- Individual Project

Took a United Nations dataset and loaded .csv into Pandas dataframe for analysis. Cleaned and analyzed data using Python code to answer questions regarding dataset. Created data visualizations using Python modules within Jupyter Notebooks.

Professional Experience:

Small Business Owner - Bail Advantage, LLC | August 2007 - August 2021

- Reported financial/operational activity to principal insurer and various government entities.
- Managed office with three partners and four agents
- Handled marketing, scheduling, supply, banking, staffing, client relations, etc.

Commissioned Officer - USAF | 1997-2007

Financial Management Specialty

 Broad experience in Financial Services, Accounting and Reporting, Budgeting, Acquisitions, and Planning and Execution requirements from local military installation, to field operations, to Air Force HQ level

Education:

Data Analytics Bootcamp, CertificationNashville Software School, Nashville, TN

Master of Business Administration

Webster University, Fairchild AFB, WA

Bachelor of Business Administration

Freed-Hardeman University, Henderson, TN